Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.1
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-flash",
"thinking_budget": 24576,
"max_subtitle_chars": 60,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING ACCURACY (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry is meticulously accurate.** They must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* for that specific segment.
*   Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **CRITICAL: Holistic Translation, Contextual Understanding & Comprehensive Analysis:**
*   **You ABSOLUTELY MUST watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative.
*   **When a single logical sentence or phrase is split across multiple subtitle entries (e.g., due to timing or character limits), you MUST mentally combine these parts to understand the full, complete meaning before translating.**
*   **NEVER translate individual subtitle entries in isolation if they are part of a larger, continuous thought or sentence.** The translation for each entry must be a coherent and accurate part of the complete, overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue in the video to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If the audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals from the video, surrounding dialogue) to infer and generate the most probable dialogue.
*   Utilize the comprehensive understanding gained from *watching the entire video* to enhance the accuracy of transcriptions, translations, and overall subtitle quality. This includes understanding nuances, resolving ambiguities, and ensuring the subtitle content aligns perfectly with what is happening visually.
*   **Example:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **Dual Language Provision & Translation Quality:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue.
*   If the original dialogue is in English, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding Japanese translation.
*   If the original dialogue is in Japanese, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding English translation.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full context of the video and any split sentences.
4.  **Readability & Formatting:**
* Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Each subtitle entry (english and japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters. Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
* Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
皆さん、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、
Everyone, welcome to Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025!
来てくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you for coming!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy it to the fullest!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never imagined.
現状
The current situation,
君もそう思った？
did you feel the same way?
最高で止まらないように
So the excitement won't end,
更新したい
I want to refresh it.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much further until I reach my dreams?
誰も行ったことない場所へ
To a place no one has ever been.
たどり着くまで僕ら止まれない
We can't stop until we reach it.
多分嫉妬いけどどうかよろしくね
You'll probably be jealous, but please be kind.
ねえねえたまに目で
Hey, hey, sometimes with your eyes,
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
something I can't create alone.
僕とか君とか私とか恋とか愛とか
Me, you, I, romantic love, and general love,
まとめて全部
all of it combined.
君を置いてどっかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going somewhere else?
ありえないよ
That's impossible.
君がくれた音にはじけた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting sparks,
はじめましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you ever since we met.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on too, it's good for us two.
一途になるほど逃げたくもなったよ
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと
Thank you for calling me,
呼んでくれてありがとう
even though I'm a mess.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人でそれがいいじゃん
From now on, it's just the two of us, that's what's best.
妄想膨らんでくストーリー
A story of fantasies growing within me.
感謝余計にへこんじゃって
My gratitude makes me feel even worse.
代償求めすぎはやあよ
Don't ask for too much compensation.
終わんない愛の連盟とでしょう
An endless love alliance, isn't it?
ねえねえおいで目で
Hey, hey, come and look with your eyes.
僕が君にできることまだまだまだあるけど
There's still so much more I can do for you.
驚かせたいから内緒なんだ
It's a secret because I want to surprise you.
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと
Your love always triumphs, you see.
許さないよ
I won't allow it.
君がいないは嫌だ
I hate it when you're not here.
わがままはただ
My selfishness is just that...
変わらない
It won't change.
知らないドキメキを絶叫しちゃうのは馬鹿
It's foolish to scream about unknown excitement.
君がくれた音にはじけた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting sparks,
はじめましてからずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you ever since we met.
君のいない未来考えらんない
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on too, it's good for us two.
一途になるほど逃げたくもなった
The more devoted I became, the more I wanted to run away.
散々な僕のこと呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling me, even though I'm a mess.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
A future without you is unthinkable.
これから先も
From now on too,
ひとり
alone.
それがいいじゃん
That's good, isn't it?
乙女
Maiden
解放で遊ぼうよ
Let's play with freedom!
ドキドキしたいじゃん
I want to feel excited.
誰だって
Everyone
反応おかしくなっちゃった
My reaction has gone strange.
アンドロイドガールを
Android girl,
おかしくなっちゃった
it's gone strange.
痛みのないキスが離れない
Painless kisses won't leave me.
僕らヴァンパイア
We're vampires.
いいよ
Okay,
吸っちゃっていいよ
you can suck me.
もう無理もう無理
I can't, I can't.
だって悪い子じゃない
Because I'm not a bad girl.
こんな歌歌ったんだって君が輝けるように
I sang this song so that you can shine.
はい。というわけで、
Alright, so,
皆さん、こんばんはでござる。
good evening, everyone!
ホロライブ6期生、強強かっこいい強運サムライ、
I'm Hololive 6th Gen's super strong, cool, lucky samurai,
風真いろはでござる。
Kazama Iroha!
はい。今年の誕生日1発目はデコニーナさんの
Yes. For my first birthday song this year,
愛言葉シリーズ4、愛言葉4を歌って踊らせていただきました。
I sang and danced to Deconina-san's "Aiko no Uta 4".
拍手いっぱい来てる。
Lots of applause!
みんなありがとう。
Thank you, everyone.
ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます！
Thank you for all the gifts and super chats too!
はい。今日ね、たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど、
Yes, today I'll be singing and dancing a lot,
感想とかあとスクリーンショットとかは
but for your impressions and screenshots,
ここ、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025で
please use #KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2025
たくさんポストしてください。
and post a lot.
振り返りの時に見に行きますからね。
I'll go and check them out when I look back!
そして今回なんと誕生日用のステージを
And this time, they even made a birthday stage
作っていただきました！
for me!
可愛い！
So cute!
ポコさん、お前ディスプレイになったんか。
Poco-san, so you've become a display, huh?
いや、どこに行ってたかと思ったら
I was wondering where you went,
ディスプレイになっておりました。
but you became a display.
はい。そして後ろにも書いてあります。
Yes, and it's also written behind me.
今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、
The title of Kazama Iroha's live is
Reversibleになってます。
'Reversible'.
素敵なロゴ。ヒイラギ先生ありがとうございました。
It's a wonderful logo. Thank you, Hiiragi-sensei!
こちらですね、みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では
I think many of you were still wondering
ちょっとあら、みたいな、どんなだろうってまだはてなはてなの方が多かったと思うんですが、
'Oh, what's it going to be like?' during yesterday's countdown,
今回これ全編見終わったらちゃんと分かるようになっておりますので、最後までお楽しみください。
but now that you've seen the whole thing, I hope it all makes sense.
そして事前に私を伝えして今ました通り、
And as I announced beforehand,
今回風真いろは100万人記念グッズが発売決定しました！
Kazama Iroha's 1 Million Subscriber goods are released!
うわー、いきなり来るよ！
Wow, it's coming suddenly!
というわけで今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので
So, I've saved up a lot of announcements again today,
ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
so I'll be interspersing them little by little.
はい。風真いろは100万人記念グッズ、こちらです。
Yes. The Kazama Iroha 1 Million Subscriber goods are here.
それでは詳細見ていきましょう。
Let's look at the details.
はい。まずはうみぼうずママが描いてくださった素敵な
First, we have a wonderful acrylic stand drawn by
アクリルスタンドに
Umibozu Mama.
風間も一筆添えさせていただいておりますので、
I have also added a handwritten message, so please
ぜひ皆さんこちらぜひお手元に
get your hands on this item, everyone!
取っていただいてメッセージっくり読んでください。
Please take your time to read the message.
ポコベもいます。
Pokobe is here too.
そして次がこちら。
And next up is this!
パブ、パブミー、パブミラー。
Pub, pub-mi, Pub Mirror!
すごいちょっと言いづらいんだよな、これリハンの時から思ってたんですけど
It's a bit hard to say, I've thought about it since rehearsals.
はい、パブミラーです。結構大きいです。
Yes, it's a Pub Mirror. It's quite big.
風間が出したグッズの中で、もうこう硬くて
Among the goods I've released, this is a hard one.
なんかこの硬い系のやつで、タオルとかはあったけど、かなり大きめになってますので
There were towels, but this hard type of item is quite large.
あの、皆さんぜひこちらもメッセージ一筆書かせていただいておりますので
Everyone, I've also written a message on this one,
ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you display it.
そしてそして次。
And next, next!
はい。
Yes.
ランダムラバーストラップ。今回は100万人にちなみまして、風間いろは今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけれども、
Random Rubber Strap. This time, commemorating 1 million subscribers,
そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきます。
and the costume from those songs has been made into a rubber strap.
なので、風を仰ぐいすとがね、実はなかなかグッズがなかったんですけど、今回のために作らせていただきました。
So, my fan items have been hard to come by, but this time, they were made specially for this occasion.
ぜひね、みんな色々集めていただとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います。
Please collect them all and use them for your Itabag creations!
次。
Next.
カードホルダー。昨今皆さんホロカとかね、いろんなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、
Card holder. Lately, there are various card goods like HoloCard and Cheki-style goods,
ついに作りましたポコベのカードホルダーです。
so I finally made Pokobe's card holder.
定期入れにしてもよし、学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです。
You can use it as a pass case or students can use it too. I'd be happy if you use it.
ぜひお気に入りの風間カードとか飾ってくださいね。
Please display your favorite Kazama cards there.
はい、それでは次。
Okay, next.
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして。
Here's what the full set looks like.
そして今回購入特典は、はい、海坊主ママ書き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきます。
And this time, the purchase bonus is a sticker newly drawn by Umibozu Mama.
今回はですね、こちら直筆サインのあの数量限定はありませんので、あの、皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね。
This time, there's no quantity limit for the handwritten signatures, so everyone can purchase them at your leisure.
はい。というわけで100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました。
Yes. And that concludes the introduction of the 1 million subscribers commemorative goods.
うわ、ドキドキって。
Wow, I'm so excited.
なんか結構安心しきってるんですけど。
I'm feeling quite relieved.
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半もあの、告知がありすぎて頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで告知いっぱいあります。
And it's not just this; there are so many announcements in the second half that I had to work hard to fit them all in. There are a lot of announcements.
なので、あの皆さん絶対に逃がさないでください。
So please don't miss out, everyone.
で、もうトレンド1位なんですか？
And is it already trending #1?
始まったばっかりだよ。
It just started!
いいの？みんなありがとう。
Is it okay? Thank you, everyone.
みんなありがとうございます。
Thank you very much, everyone.
いや、すごい。めっちゃこんなに早く行くと思わんくて皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
Wow, amazing. I didn't expect it to go so fast. It's all thanks to you all. Thank you very much.
で、ちょっとお水飲んで次の曲バシバシいきたいと思います。
Okay, I'm going to drink some water and then we'll blast through the next song.
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting!
お水いっぱい飲んだのでこの力をそのまま
I've had plenty of water, so I'll put all that
全てフルパワーで出力いたします。
power out at full force.
それでは皆殿、次の曲
Alright everyone, please listen
聞いてください。
to the next song.
大きな愛でもてなして！
Entertain me with your great love!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with your great love
そこんとこ大事なことよ
That's a very important point
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with your great love
わがままでないのよ
I'm not being selfish
私わかったの
I understood
寂しがり屋だと
that I'm a lonely person
泣きそうよ
I'm about to cry
OH YEAH!
一日の間で
Within a single day
告白をした
I confessed
OH YEAH!
一日が大人より
A single day is more
相当長いのですよ
considerably long than an adult's.
It's quite long, you know.
そうみたい
That seems to be the case.
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with your great love
そこんとこ気を揉むじゃないや
Don't you worry about that
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with your great love
ごゆっくりなさって
Please make yourself at home
みんな知らんぷり
Everyone acts ignorant,
他人のことだと
as if it's someone else's business.
違うのよ
It's not like that.
OH YEAH!
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow will be a new one
恋愛があれば
If there's love
逆張れ
then go against the grain!
OH YEAH!
大人より素直に
Be more honest than adults,
たくさん恋できちゃう
you can fall in love a lot.
You can fall in love a lot.
そうみたい
That seems to be the case.
OH YEAH!
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow will be a new one
恋愛があれば
If there's love
逆張れ
then go against the grain!
OH YEAH!
大人より素直に
More honest than adults
遠くへ
Far away
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so much
そうもみたい
I want to try that too
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so much
そうもみたい
I want to try that too
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love
ありえない幻想溢れ出す妄想
Unbelievable illusions, overflowing delusions
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
息をするように嘘ついても
Even if I lie as naturally as breathing,
あたしやっぱ いらない子？
Am I still an unwanted child?
こぼれ出しちゃった承認欲求
My overflowing desire for validation
もっとココロ満たしてよ
Please fill my heart more
アスパルチーム甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream
あたしだけに愛をください
Give your love only to me
あもう無理文字無理恋して愛して
Ah, I can't, literally, fall in love, love me
九歳執行猶予
Nine years probation
ねえ好きって言ってよ？
Hey, say you love me?
ありえない幻想溢れ出す妄想
Unbelievable illusions, overflowing delusions
つまんない欲求が散らばって
Boring desires scattered everywhere
求めてる愛情隠してるレズジョー君以外全部いらないわ
Hidden desire for love, I don't need anything but you
いらないわ
I don't need it
誰のことも見てんな
Don't look at anyone else
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of thing?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Please seriously stop with the DDs
可愛く鳴りたい
I want to be cute
キラキラしてたい！
I want to sparkle!
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
Please praise me more and more genuinely
鳴いちゃう散々開けちゃうシャンパン
I'll cry badly, I'll open champagne
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to my stream tonight, right?
独占させてよ、本命なんでしょ
Let me monopolize you, I'm your true love, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
Please support me more and more genuinely
飲み過ぎ注意オーバードーズ
Be careful not to drink too much, overdose
クラクラさせていつだって
Make me dizzy anytime
あもう無理文字無理上がって下がって九歳執行猶予
Ah, I can't, literally; up and down, nine years probation
ねえ好きって言わせてて？
Hey, let me say I love you?
噛み付いた衝動戻れない焦燥
The impulse to bite, irreversible impatience
たまんないミッドナイト
Unbearable midnight
指が絡まってときめいた表情
Intertwined fingers, a throbbing expression
何も言わないで
Don't say anything
君だけがきっと王子様
You're definitely my prince
ありえない幻想溢れ出す妄想
Unbelievable illusions, overflowing delusions
つまんない欲求が散らばって
Boring desires scattered everywhere
求めてる愛情隠してるレズジョー
The love I seek, a hidden 'les jours'
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
あたしだけずっと追いかけて！
Keep chasing only me forever!
ねえもう待ってないの
Hey, I can't wait anymore
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything but you
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shine.
もうずっとずっとずっとステージにいて
Stay on stage forever and ever and ever.
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
私がもし君のところ離れたなら
If I ever left your side,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな？
Would you be a little lonely?
意地悪く考える
I think about it maliciously.
好きな人がいるのなら内緒にしてね
If you have someone you like, keep it a secret, okay?
神様は将来の指輪をどこかに隠してる
God hides your future ring somewhere.
君の好きに合わせたんだ
I matched it to what you like,
カメレオンの色
like a chameleon's color.
私の中君だけで
Inside me, it's only you.
仮想性情はとっくへ
My virtual feelings are long gone.
責任とってね大好きです
Please take responsibility, I love you.
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
優しい目も真面目顔も
I know all your gentle eyes
全て知ってる私が言う
and serious face, I'm telling you.
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
星はちっちゃくて可愛いの
The stars are small and cute,
眩しい君が世界一だよ
but your dazzling self is the best in the world.
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
君の夢はなんですか教えて欲しい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空それが当たり前で
A sky without stars, that's just normal.
暗い道に目が慣れずに踏み出すのも怖かった
My eyes couldn't adjust to the dark road, so I was afraid to step out.
そんな時夜道へ抱く光
At that time, a light embraced the night road.
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
嫌だの声ごともわかってても
Even if I knew your voice of 'no',
君はキラキラ一生似合う
you'll always shine bright.
絶対アイドルやめないで
Don't ever stop being an idol.
一度だけでも前で感じたい
I want to feel it in front of me just once.
今日の歌い方なんか好きだな
I kinda like how you sing today.
君の努力 私の愛
Your efforts, my love,
成り立つこの関係は
this relationship thrives.
強くって
It's strong,
もらいな 越しの幸せを
May you receive it, the happiness beyond,
願った
I wished for.
でもね、だって君は
But you, because you are
アイドルよ
an idol.
ずっと
Forever,
初めて目が合った日から
since the first day our eyes met.
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Today and tomorrow, it's always you,
絶対アイドル
Absolutely an idol,
やめないで
don't quit!
これは壊れないおとぎ話
This is an unbreakable fairy tale.
恋よりもっと好きだ
I like you more than love.
頬よせ溶かして
With cheeks close, melting,
溶けないままで
yet remaining unmelted.
Woah oh oh oh oh
Woah oh oh oh oh oh
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
UNHAPPY? O, struggling child of man.
UNLUCKY? 人知らざる者も
UNLUCKY? Those unknown to man.
BE FREE 躊躇わず目指せよ
BE FREE, aim without hesitation,
生きてるんだし
you're alive!
目を凝らした過去も
Even the past you glared at,
退屈な未来も
even a boring future,
カウンセリング
needs counseling.
やめやめやめ
Stop, stop, stop,
東西ピースピース
East and West peace, peace.
アンデッド
UNDEAD
不幸？
UNHAPPY?
不運？
UNLUCKY?
アンデッド！
UNDEAD!
ねえねえねえなんだかどうして
Hey, hey, hey, somehow why
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
do I feel like I'm fighting?
慣れなくもない
I can't even get used to
過去の自分、自分、自分と
my past self, self, self.
もうとっくに死んでる
Already long dead,
透明な亡霊と対決
confronting transparent ghosts,
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
deep within painful memories.
残念？もういないのに
Regret? Even though it's already gone.
あれ？そっちがいいアイロニーね
Huh? That's good irony, isn't it?
透かされているのは
Am I being seen through?
現在の自分？
Is it my current self?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an unerasable label.
Yes! 否要はコンプレックス
Yes! No, the point is a complex,
取り憑かれてるみたい
like I'm possessed.
巻き付いたまま
Still wrapped around me,
まだ離れない在りし日の自分
the self of yesteryear that won't leave.
死んじゃいない
Not dead,
お前と前の連鎖
the chain between you and the past.
生きてることとは
To be alive is to
変わり続けることだ
keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて
Don't be content
満足するなよ
with misfortune.
幸せになろうとしないなんて
How cowardly not to
怯懦だ
try to be happy!
この世この世は
This world is a
奇々怪々ファンタジー
strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか
What will appear next,
蛇が出るか
an ogre or a snake?
出会ってやっと始まる物語
A story finally begins,
さあひとっ跳び
come on, one leap,
バイバイキスキス
bye-bye kiss kiss!
過去と未来、過去は変えられない
Past & Future can't change the Past
過去と未来、未来へ走れ
Past & Future run for the Future
かっこいい
So cool.
なんだかどうして未来になんぞ
Somehow why is there no
なんの期待も無い
hope for the future?
期待も無いような気がして
I feel like there's no hope.
もう随分生きてる
Already lived quite a bit,
既視感とテンプレで食傷
déjà vu and templates make me sick.
素敵な出来事も
Even wonderful events,
気配
are just a sign.
もう随分生きてる
I've lived quite a while
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Sadly, the karma of accumulated experience
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Hollowed-out myths and boring evolution,
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
in short, I want stimulation!
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
I'm bored, I'm used to it.
なんで 整っていくガイダンス
Why is it that the guidance and compliance
増えるコンプライアンス 蓋されていくみたい
are increasing, it feels like they're being covered up.
吸い尽くして
Sucking everything dry.
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
This and that, everything tastes the same.
死んじゃいない お前と前の連鎖
I'm not dead. The chain of you and the past,
何時の世も過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
every era, past and future, exists in the present.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill your existence honestly, a healthy
健全でハッピーエンド
and happy end.
死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
I'm not dead, I'm telling you!
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness, be human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ死んでいるも同然
Just getting used to suffering and enduring it is as good as being dead.
屍のアンデッド 人ならざるものも
The undead corpses, even those who are not human,
目指せよ
aim for it!
生きているだろう
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に光るも幸せになるも全部全部お前だ
Whether you shine in misfortune or become happy, it's all up to you!
ここんところ毎晩そうPeace Peace
It's been like this every night, peace peace.
過去と未来、過去は変えられない
Past and future, can't change the past.
過去と未来、未来へ走る
Past and future, run for the future.
人の在る所に何時も熱い事
Where people exist, there's always something passionate.
生き抜けこの化け物ばかりの物語
Survive this tale of nothing but monsters.
ヒビカセ
Hibikase
舞い降るあなたに告ぐ 音の警告
To you, who descend, a warning of sound.
協和音に酔う午前で一
Drunk on harmony, one in the morning.
あなたが触れる光撒く熱
The heat that scatters light you touch is danced
指先に踊らされ
on your fingertips.
体感 即体感
Sensory experience, immediate sensory experience.
静まる夜二人だけの密
A quiet night, a secret just for us two.
体感 即体感
Sensory experience, immediate sensory experience.
重なる波形に魅了されていく
I'm captivated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでね
Don't forget, okay?
私の声を画面越しでいい
My voice, even through the screen, is fine.
ちゃんと愛して バーチャルだって
Love me properly, even if I'm virtual.
突き放さないで まだ溺れていたい
Don't push me away, I still want to drown.
覚えていてね
Remember me, okay?
私の声をあなたが埋めた
My voice, which you filled
ここに全てを
with everything here.
見つめ合うあなたと二人重ねていたい
I want to keep our eyes meeting, and overlap with you.
音と響かせ
Let the sound echo
真夜中に問う
Asking in the middle of the night
冷え切った熱
About the chilled passion
待ち続けてる
Still waiting for
午前0時
Midnight (0 AM)
鏡写し
The mirror image,
倣わせていく
I'll imitate it
知らない
an unknown
音が伝う
sound transmits.
快感
Pleasure
疎外感
Alienation
静まる夜と
The quiet night
息遣い揃う
And synchronized breaths
体感
Physical sensation
快感
Pleasure
疎外感
Alienation
錆びたロジック
Rusted logic
今一度を焦がれる
Longing for it once again
忘れないでね
Don't forget
私の声
My voice
次元を超えて
Transcending dimensions
飛ばすシグナル
Sending signals
バーチャルだなんて言わないで
Don't say it's virtual
あなたの音に
To your sound
まだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved
覚えていてね
Please remember
私の声
My voice
あなたがくれた
Everything you gave me
この声全てを
This voice, everything
言葉と熱もね
Words and passion, too,
交わし合う
Let's exchange them
その行き先を
Their destination...
音と響かせ
Let the sound echo
あなたの産んだ音に
With the sound you created
ただ恋をしていたの
I was just in love
悲しみ狩りし
Hunting sadness
甘味関心
Sweetness and interest
全て打ち鳴らす
Ringing out everything
絶えず叫ぶ
Constantly screaming
声連ねる
Voices connect
余熱交ぜる
Mixing afterglow
愛、絶叫めく
Love, like a scream
絶えず叫ぶ
Constantly screaming
声連ねる
Voices connect
余熱交ぜる 愛、絶叫めく
Mixing afterglow, love, like a scream
魅了されていく
Being enchanted
忘れないでね
Don't forget
私の声
My voice
画面越しでいい
Through the screen is fine
ちゃんと愛して
Just love me properly
バーチャルだって
Even if it's virtual
突き放さないで
Don't push me away
あなたの音に
In your sound
まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown
覚えていてね
Please remember
私の声
My voice
あなたがくれた
The one you gave me
この声全てを
All of this voice
見つめ合うあなたと
With you, gazing at each other
交わせた生きた音を響かせ
Let the living sound we exchanged resonate
音と響かせ
Let the sound echo
あなたの初め
Your beginning
この声聞かせ
Let me hear this voice
音響かせ
Make the sound resonate
というわけで、皆さん、
So, everyone,
新衣装になりました！
I've transformed into my new outfit!
どうですか？ かっこいいですか？
What do you think? Is it cool?
かっこいいですか？
Is it cool?
なんと、今回はダンスを頑張ると決めた
Actually, I decided to try my best with dancing this time.
その時から決めていた
I decided that from the start.
ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装に
So, I've transformed into a cool dance costume!
なってみました！イェイ！
Yay!
みんな写真いっぱい撮って、撮って、
Everyone, take lots and lots of pictures!
撮って、
Take them!
イェイ、かっこいいでしょう？
Yeah, it's cool, right?
可愛いばっかなんだけど、かっこいいは
I'm always saying 'cute,' but where did the 'cool' go?!
どこ行ったんだよ！おい！かっこいいは
Hey, where did the 'cool' go?!
と、というわけで、新衣装になりました。
So, as I've become a new outfit,
ゲストパートのね、絶対アイドルやめないでから、
From the guest part, "Zettai Idol Yamenai de," then becoming solo, and then "Undead Hibikasete" will continue.
お届けさせていただきます。
I'll be sending them out to you.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ、めっちゃ頑張って、あの足ちぎれそうって
I tried really, really hard. My legs feel like they're about to tear off. Seriously, I jumped so much this time.
そういうことです。本当にたくさん今回は
My legs feel like they're about to tear off.
飛びました。足がちぎれそうです。はい。
Yes.
絶対アイドルやめないでもね、先輩方そうって
And for "Zettai Idol Yamenai de," the senpais came and it was super difficult, truly. Truly super difficult.
ラプドノ来てくれて、ありがとう、激ムズだったね。
Everyone, thank you so much for working hard together.
本当に。本当に激ムズでしたね。
Yes, yes, and also,
皆さん、一緒に頑張ってくださり本当に
I've invited many more guests after this.
ありがとうございました。そう、そう、
And also, Gozaru
そしてですね、あの、この後もまだまだ
Actually, there's more than just this coloring, so I'll be revealing that too. So everyone, please look forward to it!
ゲストさんたくさん呼んでおります。そして
Now, next, I'll be singing together with my guests.
ゴザルも実はこの、このカラーリングだけじゃ
Here you go!
ブラック★ロックシューターどこへ行ったの？
Black★Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to scream?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて私はもう走れない
Stop it already, I can't run anymore
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing
幕開け、明かりもない
Curtain rising, no light
崩れかけたこの道で。
On this crumbling path.
あるはずのないあの時の
The hope that shouldn't have been there,
希望が見えた気がした。
I felt like I saw.
どうしてブラックロックシューター。
Why, Black Rock Shooter?
懐かしい記憶。
Nostalgic memories.
ただただのまた
Just simply, those days
あの頃を。
from back then.
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
でも動けないよ。
but I can't move.
何をかける
What should I wish for?
星に願いを。
A wish upon a star.
もう一度だけ走るから。
I'll run just one more time.
怖くて震える声で
With a trembling, fearful voice,
呟く。
I whisper.
私の名前を呼んで。
Call my name.
夜明けを抱く空。
The sky embracing dawn.
強烈な体験までの距離と
The distance to an intense experience
もっと遠くない。
isn't that far.
こらえた涙が溢れそうなの。
My held-back tears are about to overflow.
下を向かないで
Don't look down,
壊してしまう。
you'll break it.
未来を生きていたいんだ。
I want to live in the future.
分かったの思い出して
I understand, remember,
強く強く信じるの。
and believe strongly.
そうブラックロックシューター
Yes, Black Rock Shooter,
優しい匂い。
a gentle scent.
言いたいことしたいこと
Things I want to say, things I want to do,
飲み込む言葉。
words I swallow.
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
動くの足。
my feet are moving.
絶対を越えて。
Overcome the absolute.
最初から分かっていた
I knew from the beginning
ここにいることを。
that I was here.
私の中のすべての勇気が
All the courage within me
火を灯して。
lights a fire.
負けないよ！
I won't lose!
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
一人じゃないよ！
you're not alone!
声を上げて
Raise my voice,
泣いたって構わない
even if I cry out loud, it's fine.
ブラックロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
見ていてくれる
will you watch over me?
今から
From now,
始まるの
it begins.
私の
My
物語
story.
隠れそうになったこの歌を
This song that was about to hide,
歌うの
I will sing it.
Beyond the way
さあ止められそうもない
It seems impossible to stop,
化学反応 起こっちゃうねえ
a chemical reaction is about to happen, hey.
もう気取って歌う愛じゃないんだ
It's not pretentious love to sing.
I'm like
I'm like,
いや無理目のクエスト
no, an impossible quest.
ノンフィクション
It's non-fiction.
You make me sigh
You make me sigh,
ナナナナ
Nannana.
I know the way.
いつだってバカ正直じゃ敵わない
I can never win
滅茶苦茶にされても変わらない
being foolishly honest. Even if
まだ暗い
I'm messed up, I won't change. Still dark.
から
So,
覚醒
awaken,
Find the way.
待って Light of appeal
Wait, light of appeal.
残酷な現実はもうない
There's no cruel reality anymore.
さんざん違うですもう聞き飽きたわ
"It's totally different," I'm tired of hearing that.
連れてってよあの高みまで
Take me to that high place.
Take me higher.
まだ無理って
"It's still impossible,"
空を拓ちゃんぜ
Let's open up the sky!
さあ止められそうもない
Come on, it's unstoppable,
化学反応
a chemical reaction.
起こっちゃうねえ
It's about to happen, hey.
もうずっとシャント言うなよ
Don't say "properly" anymore.
それが誰のせい
Whose fault is that?
終わりない夢を
Endless dreams,
描こう
let's draw them.
描いたまま
Let's keep drawing.
欲しいよ
I want them.
終わりない夜を
The endless night,
超えていこう
let's overcome it.
超えていこうこのまま
Let's keep going as we are.
辿り着く向こう側へ
To the other side we'll reach.
半歩先へ行っちゃいなよ
Take a half step forward.
操作なんてない
No control needed.
運命感じる感受性はいいんじゃね？
The sensitivity to feel fate is good, isn't it?
どちらも負けない
Neither of us will lose.
チョベホー
Chobeho!
& Brave!
追っていつもナンバーワン
Always number one, chasing.
そこは絶対
That place is absolute.
そこで成せる技
A skill achievable there.
諦めかける on my mind
I'm about to give up on my mind.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Shall we give it up or will we not?
Go beyond the way, yeah, yeah, yeah!
紡ぐ言葉を探して
Searching for words to weave
歩み研ぎ澄まし 想い仕立てがって行け
Sharpen your steps, tailor your feelings and go forth!
beyond the way comin' from my heart
うむうむうむ
Ooh-muh, ooh-muh, ooh-muh
終わりない夢を描こう
Let's draw an endless dream,
描いていこう そのまま欲しがった
let's draw it. I want it as it is
終わりない夜を越えていこう
Let's overcome this endless night,
越えていこう このまま光を
let's overcome it. Just like this, let's seek the light.
うむうむうむ
Ooh-muh, ooh-muh, ooh-muh
追いかけて合わせ出す世界を作り
Chase it, creating a world that aligns.
うむうむうむ
Ooh-muh, ooh-muh, ooh-muh
もう一生なりやまない光を
A light that will never stop shining.
always stay the way you go about the way
はい！というわけで、本日はこのお二人に
Alright! So today, these two guests have joined us!
来ていただきました！わーい！
Yay! We're so happy to have them!
やったー！
Yay!
初めてありがとう！
Thank you for coming for the first time!
あいあいあいあいあい！
Aye, aye, aye, aye, aye!
せーの！おめでとう！おめでとう！
Ready, set, go! Congrats! Congrats!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
いや、お忙しいのにお二人とも今日はね、
You're both so busy, and you came today,
ていうか、もうずっとレッスンからか。
or rather, you've been here since rehearsal.
本当に、お付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for joining me!
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
今回はですね、誕生日で実は衣装が、
This time, actually, for my birthday, a new outfit...
衣装が、一つ。
a new outfit was made.
しかも可愛いんですよね！いや、めっちゃ可愛。
And it's so cute! No, it's super cute.
おへそ、おへそ見えちゅう。
Your belly button, your belly button is showing.
やべ、取られる。
Oh no, it's exposed.
後ろ可愛いよね。ね、可愛い。めっちゃ可愛い。
It's cute from behind, right? Yeah, it's cute. Super cute.
超可愛い！
So cute!
そうなんです。新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね、
That's right. I got a new outfit for dancing,
衣装になったので、これは、恐れ多くも
so I thought, perhaps I should call
お二人を呼ぼうかな？
these two?
ダンスがうまいお二人を呼んで
I'll call these two who are good at dancing.
いやいやそんなことない。
No, no, not at all.
呼んでいいかな？え？呼んでいいかな？って、呼ばせていただきました！
Can I call them? Eh? Can I call them? So I asked them to come!
ええ！あなた、あなた方。
Oh! You, you two.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
めちゃくちゃ楽しかった。
It was so much fun.
いや、レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして。
And you both worked so hard with me in the lessons.
でも二人ともめちゃくちゃ音がうまいから、この一人だけ。
But since both of you are so good at music, it's just me.
どうしようかな？これ。
What should I do?
いやいやそんなこと。
No, no, not at all.
二人呼んで大丈夫だったかな。
Was it okay to call you two?
めっちゃ踊った。
We danced a lot.
めちゃくちゃ良かったよ。うん。
It was really good. Yeah.
めっちゃ踊った。で、最高のものが出きたと思います。
We danced a lot. And I think we created something amazing.
みんな良いものできたよねって、多分今頃コメントにはね、可愛い。ニャ。めっちゃ良かったよが流れてるとおもいます。
Everyone's probably commenting now, "It was great!" Cute. Meow. "It was really good!" is probably flowing.
逆襲嬉しい。だって、イワちゃんとは初めてじゃん、一緒にダンスするの。
I'm so happy. Because this is the first time I've danced with Iwa-chan.
まあ、こういう、こういうダンス初めて。
I mean, this kind of dance, it's the first time.
あー、練習だし。ねね
Ah, it was practice time, right?
あ、もうね
Oh, well...
めちゃくちゃ嬉しい
I'm so happy!
いや、嬉しい
Yes, I'm happy.
いや、もっと誘ってよかった。
I'm glad I invited you!
え、よかった。嬉しい。
Oh, I'm glad! I'm happy.
いや、2人と一緒にね、このね、
It was really educational to dance with
期間一緒に踊ってめちゃくちゃ勉強なりました。先生方。
both of you during this period. Teachers!
そんなことないでしょ
Oh, no, not at all.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
え、またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って
Oh, if anything comes up again, please dance with me.
え、是非あ！是非あ！
Oh, please! Please!
一緒にやりまちゃー！
Let's do it together!
やりましょう！
Let's do it!
いつでも呼んでください。
Please call me anytime.
是非やりまちょーん！
Please, let's do it!
じゃあ、ちょっとこの記念に、
Well then, as a souvenir,
この友情の証、強、強いかっこいいポーズ
a strong, cool pose as a symbol of our friendship.
写真撮っとこ、かっこい
Let's take a cool picture.
かっこいいポーズ？
A cool pose?
かっこいいポーズ。
A cool pose.
かっこいいポーズ思いつかない。
I can't think of a cool pose.
なんだ？なんだ？
What is it? What is it?
可愛いよ。
It's cute.
可愛い。
Cute.
可愛い。めちゃ可愛い。
Cute. Very cute.
可愛い。めちゃくちゃ可愛い。
Cute. Super cute.
ま、いっか。
Well, whatever.
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいね。
Everyone, please post a lot on social media.
くださいね。
Please do.
はい。
Okay.
といいつつ、実はですね
Having said that, actually...
もう一つお願いがあって。
I have one more request.
おお！おお！
Oh! Oh!
今日この後、今日初お披露目の
Later today, I'll be debuting my
オリ曲があるんですけど。
original song for the first time.
オリ曲！オリジナル！
Original song! Original!
そうなんです！楽しみ！
That's right! Looking forward to it!
そうなんです！
That's right!
楽しみ！楽しみだ！
Looking forward to it! I'm so excited!
どんな曲？
What kind of song is it?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて、
I, Kazama Iroha, wanted to be cool,
今回はかっこいい曲を、持ってまいりました！
so this time I brought a cool song!
わー！楽しみ！
Wow! I'm looking forward to it!
いっちょクール！
It's cool, yeah!
可愛くてかっこいいお二人から、
From both of you, who are both cute and cool,
やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと。
I thought I'd get a little courage before going.
かっこいいビーム？
Cool beam?
かっこいいビーム！
Cool beam!
ふあー！わー！かっこいい！
Whoa! Wow! Cool!
あ、すごい、なんか、私ちょっとイケメンになってきてる気がする。
Oh, wow, I feel like I'm becoming a handsome guy.
ちょっと待って、イケメンのポーズ分かんない。こう？
Wait, I don't know the cool guy pose. Like this?
いいよ！かっこいいじゃん！かっこいい！
You're cool! Cool!
わー！わー！
Wow! Wow!
え、いけてる気がする。
Oh, I think I'm doing it well.
いけてる！いけてる！
You got it! You got it!
よし！
Alright!
二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで、
I received so much energy from both of you,
頑張ってきます！
so I'll do my best!
頑張って！頑張って！
Do your best! Do your best!
二人とも今日は本当に、お祝いと、
To both of you, thank you so much for celebrating
そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、
with me today, and for singing and dancing with me,
そしてこの応援ビームをありがとうございました！
and for this cheering beam!
こちらこそありがとうございます。
No, thank you.
また遊びましょうね！
Let's hang out again!
はい！
Yes!
はい。じゃあそれではこの後、
Alright. Then, after this, I will be
新オリ曲を初披露目させていただきます！
debuting my new original song for the first time!
それでは、せーの、だーいちゃーん！
Alright then, ready, set, go!
見ためだけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just by looking
ワタシのこと可愛だけど
that I'm cute, but
まさか思ってないよね？
You don't really think that, do you?
ワタシの真実
The real me
知っていてほしい
I want you to know
ホントノワタシ
The true me
予測誤差の範囲と
The range of prediction errors
不測の事態も動じない
and unforeseen events won't faze me.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
Even though I put on a calm face,
心は常に青白く燃える
my heart always burns pale blue.
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
媚びたりもしない
I won't fawn,
ワタシを曲げない
I won't change myself.
扱いやすいヤツだと
If you think I'm easy to handle
思わあまく見ると痛い目見るぞ
and underestimate me, you'll regret it.
それでも時には逃げ出してしまいたい
Even so, sometimes I want to run away.
そんな衝動に弱音吐きたくなる真夜中も ある
There are midnights when I feel like being swept away by such emotions.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が
Just tiny, tiny compromises
積み重なり重なって動けない
pile up, pile up, and I can't move.
大きな大きな可能性なくし
Losing big, big possibilities,
未来を狭めてしまう
narrowing down the future.
どんなに暗くても辛くても
No matter how dark or painful it is,
後悔だけはしない
I will not regret it.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて
What's cool isn't just my appearance,
生き方なんだ
but my way of life.
現実と理想との
Even if the distance between reality
距離を縮められたとしても
and ideals could be shortened.
おすましフェイスでいるだけ
Just putting on a calm face,
何事もなかったかのように
as if nothing happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop,
後戻りもしない
I won't go back,
夢を捨てない
I won't give up on my dreams.
らしいとからしくないとか
Don't judge me by what's 'typical'
決めつけないで全部が私
or 'not typical', everything is me.
それでも時には温もりが恋しい
Even so, sometimes I yearn for warmth.
そんな感情に流されてしまいそうな夜も ある
There are nights when I feel like being swept away by such emotions.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ
I don't need the weakness that would
求めてしまうような弱さ要らない
only seek such sweet, sweet things.
苦い苦い経験だって
Even bitter, bitter experiences
ワタシを強くしてくれる
make me stronger.
から
That's why.
これがこれが
This, this is
ワタシの本当
my true self.
とても狭い狭い世界の
I don't want to end things
中だけで終わらせたくはないんだ
only in this very narrow world.
広い広い世界の果てまで
I'll run through to the ends of
駆け抜けて生きてくんだ
this wide, wide world and live!
どんなに厳しくて過酷でも
No matter how harsh or severe,
楽しんでやるさ
I'll enjoy it.
見た目じゃなくて
It's not about appearance,
生き方なんだから
it's about how you live.
はい、というわけで皆さん、ギフトパートから続けて
Alright, everyone, continuing from the gift segment,
新オリ曲「本当の私」
my new original song, "Honto no Watashi"!
歌って踊らせていただきました。
I got to sing and dance for you all.
なんと風真いろは7曲目のオリ曲です！
This is Kazama Iroha's 7th original song!
わー！
Wow!
ちょっとオリ曲のジャケットも届いているので
The jacket for the original song is here, too.
見ていきましょう。こちらです。
Let's take a look! Here it is!
はい、こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲7曲目
Yes, Kazama Iroha's new 7th original song,
「本当の私」は日付変わって19日0時より
"Honto no Watashi" will be released on the 19th at midnight.
リリースされることとなりました。今回の新衣装に
It was created in honor of this new outfit.
はい。
Yes.
ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけれども
This song is quite different from my previous ones,
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに風真いろはのこと
but many of you kindly say Iroha is cute,
かっこいいってよりも可愛いて言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので
so I wanted to show you my cool side by creating this.
いや、かっこいいとこもあるんだよって言うの伝えたくて
Please listen a lot when it's released at midnight and tell me
作らせていただきました。こちらぜひ0時にリリースされたら
your thoughts with #MiteMiteIrohadono. I'd be happy!
たくさん聞いてまた#見て見ていろは殿で感想とか教えていただけたら嬉しいです。そしてそして、ゲストパートについても話していきますかね。
And now, shall we talk about the guest segment?
じゃ、戻って。はい、ゲストでね、ミオ先輩と、そして、ハジメちゃん
Yes, I got to sing and dance with guest Mio-senpai,
ベイ先輩と一緒に歌って踊らせていただきました。
and also Hajime-chan and Bae-senpai.
ミオ先輩、そしてベイ、ね、そしてハジメちゃん
Mio-senpai, Bae, and Hajime-chan,
来てくれてありが、ありがとう！
thank you for coming! Thank you!
ほんとに歌も難しかったし、うん、べ、ベネとハジメちゃんの
The songs were really difficult, and for Bae and Hajime's parts,
やつに関してはまじこれができなすぎて一生やりすぎて、あの、一生腰痛を抱えて、これ、これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
I practiced too much. I'll have back pain for life. That's what caused my muscle aches.
はい、でもい、すごい、一緒に歌って踊らせていただきまして、とってもとってもいい経験になりました。
But it was a great experience to sing and dance with them.
皆さん、ありがとうございました。
Thank you all very much!
はい、じゃけで次の曲に行く前に、お水飲んでいいですか？
Okay, before we go to the next song, can I drink some water?
お水飲みます。お水。
I'm going to drink water. Water.
ロゴも見て、実は変わってた。よし。
Look at the logo too, it actually changed. Alright.
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
息整えて。
Let me catch my breath.
はい、次の曲なんですけれども、やっぱりみんなバラードも好きだよって言ってくれる方が多いので、今回の生
Okay, for the next song... many of you say you like ballads, so for this live...
ライブ
For this live,
バラードやろうと思って
I decided to perform a ballad,
持ってきました。はい。
so I've prepared it. Yes.
ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか色々練習したんですけど、
I practiced a lot to sing it coolly,
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので、
so I'll put my heart into it,
聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
and I'd be happy if you'd listen.
はぁ。
(sigh)
それでは、次の曲
Now, for the next song,
お聴きください。
please listen.
W/X/Y
垂れ流した
Let it flow
テレビの音
The TV's sound
溜めてしまった
I kept it in
洗濯物は今日こそ
Today's the day for laundry
晴れでもあえて
Even on a clear day
外には出ないでよ
I won't go outside
映えないスナックと
With unphotogenic snacks
アルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with alcohol
2人酸い甘いも
The two of us, both bitter and sweet
噛み合わないとしても
Even if we don't align
お互い寄り添うように
So we can cuddle close
少しずらしてみようよ
Let's shift a little
君がくれた太陽
The sun you gave me
月で隠れないよ
Don't hide with the moon
輝き弛まぬように
So it won't stop shining
歌うメロディ
The melody I sing
戯れる
Slowly flowing
Slowly flowing day
愛してるも
I love you too
通り越して
Passing through
似た者同士
Birds of a feather
こうして
Like this
年老いるまでは
Until we grow old
笑っていたいね
We want to keep smiling
君がいなきゃ
If you're not here
lonely lonely day
夢の中
In a dream
Fall asleep in bed
起こすから
Because I'll wake you
morning callのWay
With a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの
Left-off
足跡辿ると
Tracing your footsteps
不意をついて
Catching me off guard
後ろから抱きつくの
You hug me from behind
つい、繰り返すと
When I repeat it, I tend to
忘れてしまいそうになるよ
Forget it, you see
振り返ると
Looking back
日々が当たり前じゃないこと
Daily life isn't ordinary
2人の細胞
Our two cells
絡み合う特別を
Entwined in a special way
噛み締めて生きたいと思った
I wanted to live, savoring it
まどろみ抱く正午
Embracing a doze at noon
吐息漏れた体温
Breath escaping, body heat
1mmも逃がさないよ
I won't let go of a single millimeter
頭の中刻む
Carved into my mind
甘いメモリー
Sweet memory
戯れる
Slowly flowing
Slowly flowing day
愛してるも
I love you too
通り越して
Passing through
違う者同士
Different kinds of people
こうして
Like this
年老いる
Growing old
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
I want to keep smiling until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
If you're not here, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, I fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call まで
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね 離さないでいて
Don't let go of our clasped hands.
ごめん、これそがに居たいだけね
Sorry, I just want to be by your side.
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょ
The feelings we hold are mutual, right?
ほらおあいこでしょ
See, it's even.
すれ違い 間違いもあるし
There are misunderstandings and mistakes,
筋書き通りいかない 悲しみだって
and sorrows that don't go as planned.
半分こにしよう
Let's share them half and half.
別れじゃない希望 独りよがりにならないように、いつも
Hope, not separation, so I won't be alone, always.
Wow wow
君がいなきゃ 今もどこかで 動けないままの僕で
If you weren't here, I'd still be stuck somewhere,
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
unable to move. I want to tell you thank you.
これからは僕が支えてくって 呆れてしまうくらいにね
From now on, I'll support you. Even if you get fed up.
愛が増していく day by day
Love grows day by day.
面と向かうとどうしても 素直になれないな、ごめんね
When I face you, I just can't be honest. I'm sorry.
戯れる Slowly flowing
Playing around, slowly flowing.
愛してるも通り越して 似た者同士 こうして
Beyond just loving you, we're like-minded souls, like this.
年老いるまで 笑っていたいね
I want to keep smiling until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
If you're not here, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, I fall asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call まで
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい。それではですね、皆さん、
Alright, everyone,
ここまで聞いていただきまして、本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for listening until the end.
はい。こんなにちょっと歌わせていただいたんですけども、
Yes. I got to sing so much,
バラードなかなか 3Dライブでやらないので、
and ballads are quite rare for a 3D live,
すごく緊張しました。
so I was really nervous.
どうだったでしょう？か？
How was it?
わ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ拍手と、
Wow, I see so many claps
めっちゃいいってやつが、
and "very good" comments!
見える。ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
そして、ここで、
And now,
皆さんお待ちかねの、あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います。
it's time for the announcement you've all been waiting for.
ん。
Alright, here we go!
それでは元気にいきます。
Here we go, in high spirits!
それでは、ドン！
Then, here we go! Don!
風真いろは、2025誕生日記念！
Kazama Iroha, 2025 Birthday Anniversary!
出ます！イエーイ！ビジュアルが大変よろし
It's out! Yay! The visual looks great!
い！こちらのグッズが
These goods are now
販売決定です。詳細を見ていきましょう。ドン！
available for purchase! Let's check the details! Boom!
はい、まず1つ目は
First up is the
回転アクリルスタンド。
Reversible Acrylic Stand.
イラストはNardack先生に
The illustration was drawn
描いていただきました！
by Nardack-sensei!
こちらはですね、あの、こういうことです。
This is, well, it's like this.
裏表になってるって言いたい。
It's reversible.
カラーライズ衣装と新衣装で
It's reversible with the
裏表になってます。
Colorize and new outfits.
くるくる回せるので、
You can spin it around,
回して遊んでください！
so please play with it!
そして、次がこちら。
Next up is this!
はい、温感湯呑み。
A heat-sensitive teacup!
ついさっきサンプルが届いて
A sample just arrived
試しました！
and I tried it!
あったかいのを入れると、
When you pour something warm,
ポコベが出て、冷めると緑に
Pokobe appears, and when it cools,
戻りました！
it turns green again!
すごく可愛くて、お寿司屋さんにある
It's so cute, like the kind
サイズかも。ぜひ使ってね！
you find at sushi restaurants.
はい、そして次がこちら。
Alright, and next is this!
風真いろはのポップダンス衣装
Kazama Iroha's Pop Dance
バージョンのぬいぐるみです！
Outfit version plushie!
ぜひお迎えしてほしいな。
I hope you'll take one home.
みんなで遊んでね！
Please play with Goraru's plushie!
ツインテールの新衣装が
The new twin-tail outfit
ぬいぐるみになりました！
is now a plushie!
手持ちじゃなくて飾るタイプ
It's for display, not for carrying.
お家に飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
I hope you'll display it at home!
そして次は、こちら！
And next is this!
なんとござるのこれと
Look! This is Goraru's!
お揃いのこれが出ます！
It's a matching item!
ちょっと待ってね。もう一度直させて。
Wait, let me rephrase that.
これとお揃いのネックレスが
A matching necklace with
出ます！
this is coming out!
普段アクセサリーつけない方も
Even if you don't usually wear
ぬいぐるみに付けて飾ったり、
accessories, you can attach it
イベントに付けてきてくれたら
to the plushie or wear it
嬉しいです。おしゃれです！
to events. It's stylish!
ござるとお揃いにしましょ！
Let's match with Goraru!
というわけで、フルセットがこんな感じ？
So, the full set looks like this?
わー、爽やかですね！
Wow, it's refreshing!
ライブタイトルの通りリバーシブル
As the live title suggests,
で、反転があったりします。
it's reversible, so there are
そして購入特典は、こちら！
And the purchase bonus is this!
この戦争を終わらせに来ました。
I've come to end this war.
今回はグッズが2種類出るので
Since there are two types of goods,
数量限定なしで変わった特典に！
we made a unique bonus without
裏表のタロットカードが付いてきます。
It comes with a reversible tarot card.
片面には複製サインとメッセージが
One side has a replicated sign
入ってます。裏表です！
and message. It's reversible!
楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです。
I hope you enjoy it.
数量限定とかではないので
It's not a limited edition, so
ゆっくりね、あの購入していただければと思います。
please take your time to purchase it.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど、
Sales start at 9 PM after this,
ちょっと生配信の関係上ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性のが
but there's a high chance the live stream
今大なので、生配信中に皆さん、
will extend, so during the live stream,
あの、買って見に行ってください。
please go and buy it.
あ、でもあの数量限定とかないの、
Oh, but it's not a limited quantity,
ので安心してください。
so please don't worry.
はい。そしてフルセットの特典もう1つあります。
Okay. And there's one more full set bonus.
こちらです。
Here it is.
はい。みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚付いてきます。
Yes! Everyone's favorite Holoka card is included.
はい、皆さんよかったらお手に取って
So everyone, please pick it up
ホロカゼの皆さんは使ってくださいね。
and Holokaze users, please use it.
遊び方とか、あとカードの詳細は
For how to play and card details,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの
please check the official website of
公式ホームページにてご確認ください。
the Hololive Official Card Game.
よし、今台本めっちゃ見た。
Alright, I just looked at the script.
言えなかったらやばいと思って。
I thought it would be bad if I couldn't say it.
そして、こちら、一緒にこの入れさせていただきますカードは
And please note that the card included with this
日本語版のみとなっておりますので、ご了承ください。
is only available in Japanese.
はい。カートのオープンですが、こちらですね。
Okay, as for the cart opening, it's this.
100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ
Both the 1 million subscriber goods
両方同時なので、皆さんよろしくお願いします。
and birthday goods will be available at the same time.
ちょっとごめんなさい。生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
Sorry, I ran a bit over on the live stream.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信を押しとすみません。
Sorry for running over on the stream, Holo-members.
はい。というわけで、
Alright, so
ちょっとお水飲みます。
I'm going to drink some water.
はい。というわけで、あと最後の、
Alright, and as a final announcement,
お知らせとしまして、この後本編終了次第
after the main show ends,
ちょっとまた時間がね、確定た15分からか
the time will be confirmed, I think it'll be
20分からかどっちかになると思うんですけど、
either 15 or 20 minutes from now,
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定の
but there will also be an encore live
アンコールライブもございますので、
for Kazama Iroha's membership members,
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を
where I'll sing and dance to the songs
歌ったり踊ったりしますので、
everyone wanted to see, so please come
よかったら見に来てください。
and watch if you can. Thank you very much.
よろしくお願いします。メンバーシップギフトとか今日から
And thank you to all the new ambassadors
入ってくださった大使さんもありがとうございます。
who joined the membership today for gifts!
はい。そしてなんと残念なことに
Yes. And unfortunately,
次の曲が皆さんこのライブ最後の曲と、なります。
the next song will be the last song of this live.
え、皆さんもう最後は何を歌うか
Well, many of you might already be guessing
ある程度予想されている方も多いと思いますが、
what I'll sing for the grand finale,
改めてましてこの度は
but once again, thank you so much
風真いろは生誕ライブ2025
for coming to Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2025.
お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
そしてあの、制作のために一生懸命
And also, to the staff who worked so hard
頑張ってくださったスタッフさんや、
on the production, the dance instructors,
ダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、
managers, and all the creators,
皆さん本当にクリエイターの皆さんも
thank you very much.
ありがとうございました。
Honestly, it's almost a miracle that my voice
あの、正直色々あった昨年の年末から
has returned to this extent and that I can perform this live,
ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことが
especially after everything that happened since the end of last year.
ほぼ奇跡、なんだったらもう半分諦めかけて
I had almost given up.
いましたけれども、スタッフの皆様や
However, the staff and
そうのファンの対しさんたちがすごい支えてくださって、
all the fans supported me greatly.
いろんな方に支えられて本日実施することができました。
With the support of many, I was able to perform today.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
正直まだまだ本調子じゃない部分が多いのは正直なところです。
Honestly, there are still many parts where I'm not in top form.
だけど、今日少しでもこのライブを見てたくさんの人に元気が一人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
However, I hope that even a little bit of this live has reached many people and given them energy, even just one person.
これからもリアミり品川ですが、精一杯頑張って参りますので
I'll keep doing my best at Re:Milly Shinagawa, so I'll do my absolute best.
皆さん、これからもよろしくお願いします！
Everyone, please continue to support me!
はい。というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、皆さん最後に聞いてください。
Yes. And so, please listen to this song, fitting for the last one.
風真いろは、新オリ曲「君にしか読めない手紙」。
Kazama Iroha's new original song, 'A letter only you can read'.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
Thank you, if I were to write it
毎日になっちゃうくらい
It would become an everyday thing
重すぎる 私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the end
拝啓 私を
Dear You, who
形作った 君へ
created my very being
相も変わらず言葉を 届け続けて今すぐ
I continue to send words, as always, right now
届け続けて今すぐ
拝啓 未来で
Dear You, in the future
私待ってる君を
I'm waiting for you
響く音に揺れていれば
Swaying to the echoing sounds
夏を過ごすでしょうか
Will we spend the summer together?
不安がない日なんて多分なかったけど
There probably wasn't a day without worries
多分なかったけど
There probably wasn't one
私の言葉 君の言葉 重なって笑ってたんだ
My words, your words, overlapped and we laughed
ありがとう 書くとしたら
Thank you, if I were to write it
毎日になっちゃうくらい
It would become an everyday thing
重すぎる 私の想いは
My feelings are too heavy
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the end
君がいる それだけでさ
Just having you here
理由になるなんて 奇跡
is a reason, it's a miracle
ありがとう 足りないよ
Thank you, it's not enough
言葉じゃ
in words
愛してる
I love you
さぁ
Come on
魔法石のブレスレット
A bracelet of magic stones
白ツメクサのお姫様
The princess of white clover
プラスチックだらけの宝箱で
In a treasure chest full of plastic
ずっと 遊べるよ君と
I can always play with you
遊べるよ君と
I can play with you
思い出の欠片たち
Fragments of memories
溢れるこの場所で
Overflowing in this place
私の言葉 君の言葉 重ねて
My words, your words, overlapping
笑ってた
and we laughed
忘れられる世界で今
In a world where I might be forgotten,
私が選んだ生き方
this is the life I chose.
手紙をさ書いたからさ
I wrote a letter, so
この音に乗せて
let it ride on this sound.
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write 'thank you',
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would be every single day.
重すぎる私の思いは
My feelings are too strong,
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the end.
君がいるそれだけでさ
Just your presence alone
理由になるなんて奇跡
is a miracle.
ありがとう足りないのごまかすよ
Thank you, I'll make up for what's lacking.
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!